CHRIS MURPHY: Hi.
I'm here at the New York Comedy Club in New York City.
Today we're going to talk about how to have a career in comedy.
Okay.
This is "The Road Versus the City."
There are two kinds of acts--comics I should say, when they first start out; there's a road act and a city act.
In the beginning, what you want to do is be a city act in the beginning, I'll tell you why.
Many times--well, first of all, city acts will always work the road, never vice versa.
Why? 'Cause city acts is a little clique and they whisper in the owner's ear, "Oh, this guy's a hack." It's not necessarily true, but they want to keep their own position.
So you want to keep your city contacts alive.
So, work the road for money and the city for contacts.
So, in the beginning, the road work on the weekends, you'll get paid more money, anyway, so you want to do the road.
You want to build your act in the city then go out in the road.
However, don't abandon the city.
Because what happens is many television acts come out of the city 'cause many showcases in front of agents who come out to the city.
So, you want to have both worlds, okay, do 'em both.